William Winter

I am a self-taught developer with over 10 years experience in development including 7 years of commercial experience in web application development using a variety of programming languages.

London, United Kingdom contact@wwinter.co.uk

EXPERIENCE

Immediate Media Co, Hammersmith - PHP Developer

NOVEMBER 2018 - PRESENT

Working on brands such as BBCGoodFood, RadioTimes.com and Gardeners World I was helping to develop a new headless content delivery platform built on top of WordPress. While building the new headless platform I was able to work with new technologies such as Symfony, Docker, AWS (Lambda, CodePipeline & ECS) and ElasticSearch.

During my time at Immediate I have worked on a new ElasticSearch service using ElasticSearch 7 and also maintained our current ElasticSearch microservice. I also implemented a new related content module into the brands which provided better recommendations for articles a user was viewing based on our ElasticSearch weighting.

While working at Immediate we worked in an Agile environment and aimed for 100% unit test coverage on all new work completed which would be automatically blocked by our Jenkins pipeline tests and our AWS CodePipeline reports.

Technologies used: AWS, Docker, ElasticSearch, Git, Jenkins, MySQL, PHP, React & WordPress

OpenCRM, Richmond (Yorkshire), UK — Web Developer

MAY 2015 - NOVEMBER 2018

Working on a large scale web application, completing bespoke client work and developing a variety of internal applications using a multitude of programming languages. During my time here I have shown I can work well with others as I was tasked with helping the apprentice developer to increase his knowledge and get a better understanding of how we work.

Technologies used: C#, JavaScript, MySQL, PHP, SVN, VB 6 & jQuery

Global Management Platform, Sedgefield, UK — Apprentice

MARCH 2014 - MAY 2015

As an apprentice website developer I gained invaluable knowledge regarding the process of developing a web application. I undertook training courses to learn C#, VB, MS-SQL and how to use UNIX systems.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Agile - I have worked in an Agile environment and followed Agile principles.

AWS - I have used various AWS services such as ECS, Lambda and CodePipeline.

Docker - I have been able to acquire a good understanding of Docker and was able to give a talk to the rest of the team on the basics of using it.

Git - I have used Git to manage personal and freelance projects.

HTML & CSS - I can efficiently use HTML & CSS to create a responsive website which adheres to HTML standards.

JavaScript - I have an understanding of Vanilla JavaScript and how to use it to enhance a user experience.

PHP - I have a great understanding of modern PHP techniques including implementing SOLID principles.

SQL - I understand SQL queries on multiple database structures including MySQL and MS-SQL.

Testing - I can work in a test driven environment and understand the importance of automated tests.

Technologies used: C# & MS-SQL

EDUCATION

Baltic Training Services — Level 3 Software Development

MARCH 2014 - MAY 2015

After leaving school and sampling a college course I concluded an apprenticeship would prove a more successful career path for me. My apprenticeship with Baltic Training Services taught me invaluable skills in software development courses including C#, Visual Basic, MS-SQL, Unix, Software Development Process & Testing and Customer Services. During my time at Baltic I gained commercial experience which has since allowed me to advance my software development career.

ABOUT ME

After working in the North East for 4 years I decided to relocate to London to seek further opportunities to improve my career and explore what London has to offer. When I am not working I am either playing games or out exploring London, usually a pub, with friends.

REFERENCES

References are available upon request.